familychristian.com 2016-12-29

# Privacy Policy

## Our commitment to You, Our Customer

FamilyChristian.com respects and wants to protect the privacy of our users. We do not sell, rent, or loan any identifiable information regarding our customers to any third party. Any personal information you give us will not be given to other third parties without your consent.

## Use of IP Addresses

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers identify your computer by its IP address. FamilyChristian.com uses your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your shopping cart and to gather broad demographic information.

## Use of Cookies

Cookies are files that your Web browser places on your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. FamilyChristian.com creates and then uses these cookie files to track your clicks as you go through the FamilyChristian.com website. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you will find them at most major websites.

The information we retrieve from the cookie files helps us track user trends and patterns. We use the information from cookies to provide services that better fit our users' needs. FamilyChristian.com also uses cookies to deliver content specific to your interests.

You may occasionally get cookies from our advertisers. FamilyChristian.com does not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-party servers is standard in the Internet industry.

## Use of Information

FamilyChristian.com will not collect any personal information about individuals except when specifically and knowingly provided by the individual. Examples of personal information include, name, e-mail address, mailing address and phone number. FamilyChristian.com may share non-personal aggregate or summary information regarding its customers with partners or other third parties, but we do not sell, rent, or loan any customer level identifiable information to anyone, except that FamilyChristian.com may be required to disclose personal information by applicable law or in connection with the enforcement of FamilyChristian.com contract or property rights, and except that information collected by FamilyChristian.com may be transferred in connection with the sale or merger of the company or any division or business line of the company to which the information relates. If you make a purchase through FamilyChristian.com, your credit card information will be provided to our credit card processor.

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (like their name and email address) and unique identifiers (like a password). We use customer contact information from the registration form to send the user information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Unique identifiers (such as passwords) are collected to verify the user's identity, for use as account numbers in our record system, and for other purposes. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor the visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address) and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and information about our company to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services.

Our online surveys and promotions ask visitors for contact information (like their email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States . Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. If you would like to prevent your data being used by Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Our company and our trusted third parties may share with one another anonymous versions of user information collected at this site. We may use that information to link to and issue anonymous cookies containing demographic or intent-based data for online behavioral advertising purposes. Such cookies do not contain personally identifiable information. If you would like to opt out of online behavioral advertising, click on one of these links: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> or <http://networkadvertising.org/choices>.

## Security

At FamilyChristian.com protecting your personal information through online security is of the utmost importance. Thus, we have taken reasonable means to ensure that before your information is transmitted across the Internet, it is encrypted to prevent the information from being read or tampered with during the transmission. Our site uses the industry standard, SSL (secured socket layer) encryption.

If you use one of the following browsers then SSL encryption is protecting your information:

  * Microsoft Internet Explorer 3.0 or higher
  * Mozilla FireFox 1.5 or higher
  * Netscape 2.0 or higher
  * America Online 3.0 or higher

While we at FamilyChristian.com consider online security a priority, we cannot provide absolute assurances against, and will not be liable for, any breaches of confidentiality due to system failures or unauthorized access by third parties.

## Mobile Giving

A one-time donation of $10.00 will be added to your mobile phone bill or deducted from your prepaid balance. Donor must be age 18+ and all donations must be authorized by the account holder (e.g. parents). By texting YES, the user agrees to the terms and conditions. All charges are billed by and payable to your mobile service provider. Service is available on most carriers. Donations are collected for the benefit of Family Christian Ministries by the Mobile Giving Foundation and subject to the terms found at [www.hmgf.org/t](http://www.hmgf.org/t). Message & Data Rates May Apply. You can unsubscribe at any time by texting STOP to short code “91011”; text HELP to “91011” for help.

## Mobile Terms & Conditions

Please click [here](http://www.familychristian.com/text) to learn more about our Mobile Terms & Conditions.

## Choice/Opt-out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

  1. You can send email to: [customerservice@familychristian.com](mailto:customerservice@familychristian.com)

  2. You can call the following telephone number: 616-554-8700

## Correct/ Update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

  1. You can send email to: [customerservice@familychristian.com](mailto:customerservice@familychristian.com)

  2. You can call the following telephone number: 616-554-8700

## Contacting the website

If you have any questions about this Privacy and Security Statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Familychristian.com   
5300 Patterson Ave SE  
Grand Rapids, MI 49530  

## Use of website

This website is intended for use only by individuals who are 13 years of age or older. If you are not at least 13 years of age, do not submit any information to this site.

Use of this site will constitute your acceptance of this privacy policy.
